Privacy Policy

Document Ref. Website Privacy Policy

Version: 8.5

Dated: January 14th 2021

Document Author: Hilde Instefjord

Privacy Policy

Index

Who we are 3

Introduction 4

How we collect your information 4

Why we collect your information 4

Information storage and security 5

3rd party Systems and Processors 5

When you use our website 5

Cookies 5

Web beacons 6

UTM codes 6

Google reCAPTCHA 6

Why do we collect this information? 6

What do we do with your information? 7

How long do we keep your information? 7

Additional rights as a data subject 7

When you submit an inquiry via our website, email or social media 7

Why do we collect this information? 8

What do we do with your information? 8

How long do we keep your information? 9

Additional rights as a data subject 9

When you purchase a license or subscription from our website 9

Why do we collect this information? 9

What do we do with your information? 10

How long do we keep your information? 10

Additional rights as a data subject 10

When you sign up to receive content from our website 11

Why do we collect this information? 11

What do we do with your information? 11

How long do we keep your information? 12

Additional rights as a data subject 12

When you use our JS product suite, Wrappers, Editor and/or CDN 12

When you use our Export Server 12

What do we do with your chart data? 13

How long do we keep your data? 13

Additional rights as a data subject 13

Version 8.5 Page 2 of 17

Privacy Policy

When you submit a survey, participate in a competition, submit code or blog, or apply for

a job 13

Why do we collect this information? 14

What do we do with your information? 14

How long do we keep your information for? 14

Additional rights as a data subject 15

Your rights as a data subject 15

Your right to complain 15

Legal Requirements 16

Retention 16

Right to be forgotten 16

Our Policy Toward Children 16

Updates to this privacy policy 17

Version 8.5 Page 3 of 17

Privacy Policy

Who we are

We are Highsoft AS. Our address is Sentrumsgata 44, 6893 Vik i Sogn, Norway.

You can contact us by postal mail at the above address, or by email at privacy@highsoft.com.

You can read more about us here.

In collecting information about you, we are acting as a data controller and we are required to

provide you with information about why and how we collect and use your data, and about the

rights you have over your data.

We are not required to have a data protection officer. Any inquiries about our use of your

personal data should be addressed to the contact details above.

Introduction

Highsoft is committed to protecting your privacy and will make every commercially viable

measure to secure your data according to European Union’s General Data Protection

Regulation (GDPR) guidelines. Any and all information collected is safeguarded according to

the applicable legislation concerning personal data and is updated to comply with the GDPR.

This privacy policy outlines the information, including any personal data we collect when you

use and interact with our website and services.

How we collect your information

In the course of providing content, products, and services to our visitors and customers, we

collect or receive information about you in different ways.

You provide some data directly, and some data we get by collecting data about your

interactions, usages, and experiences with our website, products, and services. When collecting

your data we will give you the chance to choose what information to provide for e.g. enabling us

to market and promote products or services.

We collect and process personal data about you only where we have a legal basis for doing so

under applicable European Union (EU) laws, even if you are located outside the European

Economic Area (EEA).

Why we collect your information

We collect information in order to be able to understand, analyze and improve our website and

services. In some cases, we may require certain information in order to provide certain products

and services and to ensure our services and offerings are performing optimally and to protect

our, and your legal rights and interests.

Version 8.5 Page 4 of 17

Privacy Policy

Information storage and security

We rely on third-party partners to collect data about you and your use of our website and

services as well as for some of the features and functionality. We have Data Processing

Agreements (DPA) with all third-party data processors that commits them to provide an

appropriate level of safeguards for your personal data, which includes compliance with GDPR.

Most of our data is collected and processed within the EEA. For processing that is taking place

outside EEA, we have provided appropriate safeguards to ensure our partners accept the EU

Standard Contractual Clauses (SCC) for International Data Transfers.

3rd party Systems and Processors

We have DPAs with all our Processors, and they all adhere to the Payment Card Industry Data

Security Standard (PCI DSS) for Service Providers.

Below you will find more information about how we collect and process information, including

how we use third-party partners in connection with our services.

When you use our website

Our legal basis for collecting the information described in this section is based on legitimate

interest, in reference to Article 6-1(f) of the GDPR, or consent in reference to Article 6-1(a) of the

GDPR.

This section details the information we collect from you when you use our website to browse our

products and services and view the content we make available.

Cookies

Cookies are small pieces of text sent by a website and stored on your computer by your web

browser. A cookie file is stored in your web browser and allows the service or a third-party to

recognize you and make your next visit easier and the service more useful to you.

Please refer to our Cookie Policy for detailed information on which cookies we set when visiting

our website and using our services, including what purpose each serves.

We use JSFiddle to display code demos and samples on our webpages and on our blog.

JSFiddle does not track personal data but sets a session cookie to prevent cross-domain

attacks in the embedded code samples. Please refer to JSFiddle - Terms \& Conditions and

JSFiddle - Privacy Policy for additional information.

Version 8.5 Page 5 of 17

Privacy Policy

We use website analytics services called Google Analytics, Google Ads, and Google Tag

Manager to record usage and performance data of our website and web-services. We will also

use a marketing automation tool to gather certain website data related to campaigns.

We analyze aggregated anonymized data based on e.g. the date you visit the site, how often

you come to this site, what pages you visit when you do so, and what other sites you used prior

to coming to this site, observing trends, visitor numbers and behavior. We have ensured that the

data we collect through website analytics services are anonymized in such a manner that it can

not be used to re-identify you by e.g. excluding IP addresses or your detailed location. If you

consent to us using Statistics cookies in our consent manager, we additionally use Google

Analytics built-in demographic, and extended ecommerce tracking to the same end. This

tracking provides aggregated data on Age, Gender, Affinity Categories, In-Market segments,

and other categories, along with Purchasing Information (Product, Quantity) from our web-shop

in the event a purchase is made. Demographics data is collected by Google and its Affiliates,

and shared with Highsoft in an aggregated form. Google and its Affiliates may use collected

data for targeted advertising. Further details on how Google collects, processes, and stores this

data can be found here. The use of Statistics cookies requires that you give your consent in our

cookie declaration. You may also prevent data from being used by Google Analytics by

installing the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on.

Web beacons

Pages on our site and emails we send to our users may contain web beacons. Web beacons

(also referred to as clear gifs, pixel tags, and single-pixel gifs) are small electronic file references

that are embedded onto a web page or an email to analyze traffic, for example, whether a user

has successfully opened an email, visited a page or completed a purchase.

In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, web beacons are

rendered invisibly on web pages when you open a page.

UTM codes

We may also make use of UTM codes. These are strings that are appended to a URL (the

“Uniform Resource Locator,” which is typically the HTTP or HTTPS address entered to go to a

web page) when a user moves from one web page or website to another, where the string can

represent information about browsing, such as which promotion, page, or publisher sent the

user to the receiving website.

UTM codes are used to enhance our web analytics solutions to understand, for example, if the

visitor’s journey on our site started with a newsletter or ad campaign. Any analytics gathered on

the basis of UTM codes are, and will remain, anonymous and analyzed in aggregate form.

Version 8.5 Page 6 of 17

Privacy Policy

Google reCAPTCHA

In the prevention of spam and abuse, we use the reCAPTCHA feature of Google on our

website. This function is primarily used to distinguish whether an input is made by a natural

person or abusive by automated processing. The service includes the sending of the IP address

and possibly other data required by Google for the reCAPTCHA service to Google. Additional

information about Google reCAPTCHA and Google's privacy policy can be found here.

Hotjar user behavior tracking

When consenting to Statistics cookies in our consent manager, we use Hotjar in order to better

understand our users’ needs and to optimize this service and experience. Hotjar is a technology

service that helps us better understand our users’ experience (e.g. how much time they spend

on which pages, which links they choose to click, what users do and don’t like, etc.) and this

enables us to build and maintain our service with user feedback. Hotjar uses cookies and other

technologies to collect data on our users’ behavior and their devices. This includes a device's IP

address (processed during your session and stored in a de-identified form), device screen size,

device type (unique device identifiers), browser information, geographic location (country only),

and the preferred language used to display our website. Hotjar stores this information on our

behalf in a pseudonymized user profile. Hotjar is contractually forbidden to sell any of the data

collected on our behalf.

For further details, please see the ‘about Hotjar’ section of Hotjar’s support site.

Why do we collect this information?

Some tracking mechanisms are considered necessary and are required in order to provide

certain functionality like navigation and search. Other tracking mechanisms are essential for us

in order to understand how our visitors find and use our site. We also monitor our website

performance, such as what pages our visitors navigate to in order to understand how to improve

our service and offerings, as well as measuring marketing efforts and user experience to ensure

intended and proper functionality.

If you do not want us to track your website interactions, you may revise your cookie preferences

on our website. We will not deny you access to our site or services should you choose to

decline the use of such tracking mechanisms, but when declined, there may be cases where the

user experience is not optimal.

What do we do with your information?

Besides the functionality necessary for our website and services to function, we may use

portions or aggregated numbers for internal marketing presentations or use Google Data Studio

for analytics.

We do not share or sell any information collected, even when anonymized.

Version 8.5 Page 7 of 17

Privacy Policy

Google provides some additional privacy options for Google Analytics cookies.

How long do we keep your information?

The information we collect will be anonymised and kept for a maximum of 38 months. Google

provides some additional privacy terms.

Additional rights as a data subject

In collecting this information, we are acting as a data controller and you have additional rights

with regards to the data we store and process, which is outlined in the section below called

‘Your rights as a data subject’.

When you submit an inquiry via our website, email or social media

Our legal basis for processing and collecting your personal data when you contact us via our

website or by email, is based on contractual obligations in reference to Article 6-1(b) of the

GDPR.

Our legal basis for collecting information on you when you contact us via Social Media is based

on our legitimate interest to provide you with the most accurate response in a timely manner in

reference to Article 6-1(f) of the GDPR.

When you submit an inquiry via our website or send an email, we may ask you for your

company name, email address and a brief description of your inquiry. We will ask for a minimum

set of information in order to reply to technical or sales support questions, or other inquiries.

When you ask us a question in Social Media, like Facebook, Twitter, Instagram or LinkedIn, we

will reply to your inquiry directly on that platform. No data will be sent automatically to other

systems, although we encourage you to contact us via our website.

We will also have access to aggregate insights to visitor activity on our social media accounts,

as well as any individual public activity, such as liking, posting or commenting on our accounts.

For all interactions on our social media accounts, we hold a shared data controller role of your

data along with the social media platform. This means that all information posted on our social

media accounts will also be available to that social media company.

In order to learn more about such companies' use of personal data, please visit the respective

social media company’s privacy notice.

Why do we collect this information?

We use the information you provide in order to respond and hopefully to provide you with the

information you need, including providing Support or fulfilling steps required prior to entering into

a contract e.g. as part of pre-sales activity.

Version 8.5 Page 8 of 17

Privacy Policy

We may also email you several times after your inquiry in order to follow up on your interest and

ensure that we have answered to your satisfaction.

What do we do with your information?

Regardless of how you contacted us, we may share your question/problem in our internal email

provided by Google or chat platform provided by Slack for internal support in providing you with

a solution but will exclude any personal data.

Your sales-related inquiry is stored and processed in our CRM and also as an email.

We might share your name, email, and company name with our partners, for the sole purpose of

performing sales activities and providing information that we think will be of interest to you with

respect to your inquiry. Our partners will have access to the minimum of information needed.

Technical Support inquiries are stored and processed in our Support Ticket system and also as

an email.

Our first line support inquiries are handled by our partner, Black Label. Our partners will have

access to the minimum of information needed to provide support.

Your name, email, and company name is also sent to marketing automation tool for the sole

purpose of sending you information that we think will be of interest to you with respect to your

inquiry.

How long do we keep your information?

Inquiries you make that are not of a financial or legal nature (e.g. purchasing a product or

service) will be removed from our records if you are inactive for more than 2 years, unless you

explicitly consent to us storing your information for the purposes of keeping you updated on our

products and services (in such a case, see below ‘when you sign up to receive Newsletters’ on

how we handle your data).

Additional rights as a data subject

In collecting this information, we are acting as a data controller and you have additional rights

with regards to the data we store and process, which is outlined in the section below called

‘Your rights as a data subject’.

When you purchase a license or subscription from our website

This section outlines the information we collect from you when you purchase a product from our

website. Our legal basis for processing and collecting your personal data is based on fulfilling

Version 8.5 Page 9 of 17

Privacy Policy

legal obligations in reference to Article 6-1(c) of the GDPR or contractual obligations in

reference to Article 6-1(b) of the GDPR.

When you purchase from us, we ask you for your name, billing address, email address,

company name, and we collect your IP address, and credit card details.

Documents related to the purchase like e.g. Purchase Order, Custom license agreement, and

other relevant information related to the purchase will be stored in our CRM system and in our

Cloud storage space.

When you register for a non-commercial license, we ask for your name, email address, intended

usage, and the organisation name, to verify the free usage. This information and a copy of your

License information will be stored in our CRM and in our Marketing Automation tool.

Why do we collect this information?

This information is required in order to process your payment, deliver products or services, and

to comply with applicable tax/revenue laws. We will use your email address to send you a

receipt after purchase and contact you regarding your purchase or otherwise ask for information

necessary to fulfill our contract with you.

What do we do with your information?

We use third-party vendors to store and process payments, and they all adhere to the PCI Data

Security Standard (PCI DSS) for Service Providers. Your name, billing address, email, company

name and other optional information you provide during the purchase process is stored in our

e-commerce platform, and CRM.

From June 30th 2020, our e-commerce platform is hosted by Convert Group AS. For a limited

time period, your data will continue to be hosted Visma AS, as we phase out this previous

processor. Our CRM is hosted by Salesforce.

As payment providers we use Nets, American Express and PayPal.

Your IP address, email address, credit card details are passed on to Nets, PayPal or American

Express. Highsoft does not store or process your credit card or PayPal information (with the

exception of the e-mail address attached to your PayPal account).

Wire transfers go through DNB Bank ASA.

Your name, email, company name, and License information is sent to our marketing automation

tool for the sole purpose to follow up on your license and support term, including relevant

product updates.

Anonymized data may also be sent to Google Data Studio for analyzing our performance

internally.

Version 8.5 Page 10 of 17

Privacy Policy

We do not use the information you provide to make any automated decisions that might affect

you.

For more information please see Privacy Policy for Online Purchase here.

How long do we keep your information?

Information about the transaction is kept for however long necessary to comply with applicable

tax/revenue laws, which under current laws is 10 years.

Additional rights as a data subject

In collecting this information, we are acting as a data controller and you have additional rights

with regards to the data we store and process, which is outlined in the section below called

‘Your rights as a data subject’.

When you sign up to receive content from our website

This section outlines the information we collect from you when you sign up to receive content

from our website by signing up to receive newsletters or notification of product updates or when

you download whitepapers or tutorials.

Our legal basis for processing and collecting your personal data is based on consent in

reference to Article 6-1(a) of the GDPR.

When you sign up to receive content from our website, we will ask you for your first name and

email address, and optionally other information about your interests and preferences, etc. We

will collect your IP address and information about what kind of content that you engage with,

e.g. which stories you want to learn more about by clicking on “read more” links next to story

summaries.

Upon registration you will receive an email to confirm your registration. Unless you act upon that

email, you will not be enrolled in our database.

Why do we collect this information?

The email address will be used to periodically provide you with news and information about our

products and services, which we feel might be of interest to you. We ask for your first name

because we are on a first-name basis with all our friends. Other optional information we ask for

will be used to make sure we send you relevant information and to spot trends. We collect your

IP address to prevent fraud and identify geographical clusters of customers so we may serve

you better.

Version 8.5 Page 11 of 17

Privacy Policy

We use web beacons to detect whether you have opened the email we send or not. This is to

keep track of your engagement and ensure we send you relevant information or if you have

been inactive for more than the retention limit, we will ensure that your email will be deleted

from our database.

Read more about web beacons here.

We use UTM codes to identify specific sources of traffic and to customize content but never

used for profiling or other, user identifiable, tracking.

Read more about UTM codes here.

What do we do with your information?

The information you provide when you sign up to receive content from our website is stored and

processed in our self-hosted Marketing automation tool and in our CRM hosted by Salesforce.

We might share your name, email, and company name with our partners, for the sole purpose of

performing sales activities and providing information that we think will be of interest to you with

respect to the content you have received. Our partners will have access to the minimum of

information needed to perform their duties.

We may ask for your consent to retain your information in our systems in order to send you

further information that we think may be of interest to you.

How long do we keep your information?

Your information is kept for as long as you continue to engage with our content, but we cease to

send you information and content and will remove your data from our records if you are inactive

for more than 2 years. Inactive, in this respect, means that you have not read any of the emails

we have sent you, or downloaded any content from our website. You may unsubscribe at any

time by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any email you receive or by contacting us

to revoke your consent, which will result in the prompt removal of your information from our

database, along with any data regarding your engagement with our content.

Additional rights as a data subject

In collecting this information, we are acting as a data controller and you have additional rights

with regards to the data we store and process on you, which are outlined in the section below

called ‘Your rights as a data subject’.

When you use our JS product suite, Wrappers, Editor and/or CDN

When you buy a license for Highcharts JS including any other offering like e.g., Highcharts

Maps, Highcharts Stock, Highcharts Gantt, Highcharts iOS, Highcharts Android, Highcharts

Editor, or any other Wrapper or plugin, we have access to the information you provide when

Version 8.5 Page 12 of 17

Privacy Policy

purchasing. This is limited to information necessary to process your payment as detailed above

in When you purchase a product from our website.

The products are downloadable, and we do not track further usage of it, except as set forth

herein.

When you use our Export Server

This section outlines the information we collect from you when you use our Export Server. If you

choose to make use of this service, our legal basis for collecting information falls under the

premise of contractual obligations in reference to Article 6-1 (b), as this is a service that you can

use optionally, when you have purchased a license from us, and by using it, you agree to us

processing your chart - data. The export server is not to be used in cases where charts may

contain personal data. In such cases the Export server must be self-hosted, or alternatively the

offline export module can be used.

The export server converts either a chart configuration (in JSON format) or a vectorized chart (in

SVG format) to one of several possible output formats (namely PNG/JPEG/SVG/PDF). This is

offered as a service to our customers in order to convert charts to e.g. print-ready formats.

When using the export server, either as an API service or indirectly through the export module

in Highcharts Products Suite, your chart is sent to our server. This is the default behavior of the

export module. We also have an offline export module that operates without the need for a web

service, however, this is not fully compatible with all browsers and formats.

The file is publicly available, as it must be for the service to work, however, the filenames are

created using UUID’s and as such, it is highly unlikely that anyone would be able to guess the

filenames within the lifespan of the files. The export server itself is also fully open-source, so

you are free to host your own server should your company policies require more control over the

exporting process.

What do we do with your chart data?

We use the chart data in order to convert your chart to the desired output format.

How long do we keep your data?

When not using async exporting, the result from the chart export will be stored on our server for

15 minutes before it deletes itself.

Additional rights as a data subject

In collecting this information, we are acting as a data controller and you have additional rights

with regards to the data we store and process, which is outlined in the section below called

‘Your rights as a data subject’.

Version 8.5 Page 13 of 17

Privacy Policy

When you submit a survey, participate in a competition, submit code

or blog, or apply for a job

This section tells you about the information we collect from you when you submit a survey,

participate in a competition, submit code examples or blog to us via our website. Our legal basis

for processing and collecting your personal data is based on consent Article 6-1(a) of the

GDPR.

Along with your contribution, we may ask you for your email address, and optionally other

information about your interests, preferences, opinion, etc. as relevant to the particular

submission.

Why do we collect this information?

Depending on your inquiry we will e.g. need personal data to contact you, highlight your

contribution on our website, to evaluate if you are a candidate for a job, and other relevant

information pertaining to the nature of the inquiry. We will not collect or accept this information

without your explicit consent.

What do we do with your information?

We will store and process the information you share with us in our Marketing Automation tool or

HR-tool depending on the type of request. We may in some cases use Google forms when

conducting Surveys. Your reply will then be processed by Google. Please refer to Google’s

Privacy Policy for information.

We may publish your submission to our website, in the event that was the purpose of the

submission. Further details will be provided upon initial contact. We will use your information to

provide the information you need related to your inquiry.

We may ask for your consent to retain your information in our systems in order to send you

further information that we think may be of interest to you. We will only send you updates and

information for as long as you continue to consent. You may unsubscribe to such automated

contact at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any email newsletter you

receive.

If you post a comment on our site, we won’t use your email address except to send you

update-notices about the specific entry you commented or to initiate a private one-to-one email

conversation with you about your post.

How long do we keep your information for?

Your information is kept for as long as you continue to consent, but we cease to send you

updates and will remove your data from our records if you are inactive for more than 2 years.

Inactive, in this respect, means that you have not read any of the newsletters we have sent you.

Version 8.5 Page 14 of 17

Privacy Policy

You may opt-out such updates at any time, which will result in the prompt deletion of any

non-legal or financial information we have about you.

When you apply for a job, your information will be removed from our database once the position

is filled, or until - if applicable - you are no longer considered for the position. The information

will not be stored for longer than 3 months after your submission.

Additional rights as a data subject

In collecting this information, we are acting as a data controller and you have additional rights

with regards to the data we store and process, which is outlined in the section below called

‘Your rights as a data subject’.

Your rights as a data subject

By law, you can ask us what information we hold about you and ask to have it corrected if it is

inaccurate.

If we have asked for your consent to process your personal data, you may withdraw that

consent at any time, and you can request that your data be erased.

If we are processing your personal data for reasons to fulfill a contract, you can ask us to give

you a copy of the information you have provided for us in a machine-readable format so that you

can transfer it to another provider.

You have the right to ask us to stop using your information for a period of time if you believe our

processing is not lawful.

We will not make automated decisions on the basis of the personal data we have collected.

You may not ask to delete, or substantially change, is financial transaction data we are required

to retain for 10 years for legal, tax or accounting purposes.

To submit a request regarding personal data by email, please use the contact information

provided above in the Who Are We section of this policy.

Your right to complain

If you have a complaint about our use of your information, we would prefer you to contact us

directly in the first instance so that we can address your complaint.

We are not required to have a data protection officer, so for any inquiries about our use of your

personal data, please use the contact information provided above in ‘Who are we’ or contact us

through our data subject request form.

Version 8.5 Page 15 of 17

Privacy Policy

Legal Requirements

We might need to disclose personal data of users based on requirements by law. This might

result in legal obligations or urgent needs to suspend or block an account. In such an event we

will aim to notify the user that is affected by such actions.

Highsoft may also retain, preserve, or release person in response to lawful requests by public

authorities, including to meet legitimate security or law enforcement requirements; to protect,

establish, or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims, including to collect a debt;

or investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, threats to our

property, or violations of our Standard License Agreement for our JS products, or your

customized Agreement.

Retention

Highsoft will retain and use your information only as long as it is necessary for the purposes set

out in this policy, and to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve

disputes, enforce our agreements, and as otherwise described in this policy.

Specifically, Highsoft will retain your information for as long as you have an active service

account with us, for as long as you remain subscribed to our newsletter, or as needed to provide

the services to you. The exception to this is data arising from a financial transaction, which we

are required by local tax and accounting laws to store for 10 years.

Right to be forgotten

If you have not interacted with our sales team, support team, subscribed to any of our

newsletters or utilized any of our products and services, for 2 years, and your contact

information is not necessary per the Retention policy above, we will automatically delete your

records from our databases. The only exception is if you send us a job application. In this

instance, we will keep your application for a maximum of three months.

Our Policy Toward Children

Our services are not intended for users under the age of 13, and we do not knowingly collect or

maintain information of such individuals. We encourage parents and guardians to monitor their

children’s online activities.

Updates to this privacy policy

We regularly review and, if appropriate, update this privacy policy from time to time as our

services and use of personal data evolves. If we want to make use of your personal data in a

Version 8.5 Page 16 of 17

Privacy Policy

way that we haven’t previously identified, we will contact you to provide information about this

and, if necessary, to ask for your consent.

We will update the version number and date of this document each time it is changed.

Version 8.5 Page 17 of 17
